我来这里只是出于对我父母的尊重，他们...
I only came here out of respect for my parents who...
认识你的家人。
Knew your family.
你父亲不仅仅是我家人的朋友。
Your father was more than just a friend to my family.
那是很久以前的事。
That was a long time ago.
是的。
Yes.
很长时间。
A long time.
托马斯韦恩相信我父亲。
Thomas Wayne believed in my father.
他相信一个人可以为混乱的世界带来秩序。
He believed a man could bring order to a world of chaos.
你呢，布鲁斯？
And you, Bruce?
我相信哥谭市。
I believe in Gotham city.
你试试 Vongole？  毫米。可口的。
You try the vongole?  Mm. Delicious.
哦。唔。
Oh. Hmm.
布鲁斯大师。万圣节快乐。
Master Bruce. Happy Halloween.
有咖啡吗？  在研究中，先生。
Is there coffee?  In the study, sir.
凯尔小姐打来电话。
A miss Kyle telephoned.
她说她正在检查你给她的号码，以确保它是真实的。
She said she was checking the number you gave her to make sure it's real.
大门是敞开的。我们已经很多年没有见过骗子了。
The gates are open. We haven't seen a trickortreater in years.
我们今晚不会看到一个。
We won't see one tonight.
几乎不值得冒安全风险，你不是说吗？
Hardly worth the security risk, wouldn't you say?
尊敬的先生，
Respectfully, sir,
如果我们的安全依赖于价值 600 美元的铁合金......
if our security is dependent on $600 worth of iron alloy...
这座城市已经沦陷了，阿尔弗雷德。
This city is fallen, Alfred.
那么我们必须努力再次把它举起来，布鲁斯。
Then we must endeavor to lift it up again, Bruce.
与此同时，我们生活在顽固的希望中。
In the meantime, we live in obstinate hope.
还有一个没有上锁的豪宅。
And an unlocked mansion.
反正...
Anyway...
这是一个荒谬的假期。
It's an absurd holiday.
哦是的。穿上戏服和惊人的恐惧。
Oh, yes. Putting on costumes and striking fear.
很荒谬。
Quite absurd.
你真的觉得...
Do you really think...
我讨厌他那样做。
I hate when he does that.
哇。哇，哇。
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
詹姆斯，宝贝们！不跑！
James, babs! No running!
来吧，伙计们，慢点。你会伤害自己的。
Come on, guys, slow down. You're gonna hurt yourselves.
他们很兴奋，吉姆。重要的夜晚。
They're excited, Jim. Big night.
是的。好的。但我们要乘坐警车。
Yeah. All right. But we're taking the squad car.
疯子太多了。
Too many crazies out.
先生！
Sir!
不挂断。
Hang on.
现在，你准备好了。
Now, you're ready.
好吧，谁想开车？
All right, who wants to drive?
吉姆！
Jim!
开玩笑而已。
Just joking.
嘿嘿，坚持住。
Hey, hey, hang on.
这可能是一个错误的号码，或者一个骚扰电话或......
It could be a wrong number, or a crank call or...
戈登。
Gordon.
嗯...
Uhhuh...
什么时候？
When?
好的。我在路上
All right. I'm on my way.
现在是你父亲的船长。
Your father's captain now.
整个部门都指望他了。
The whole department's counting on him.
嗯，我也指望他了。
Well, I was counting on him, too.
我会尽量快点。
I'll try and be quick.
你好？
Hello?
吉尔达，你来了。
Gilda, there you are.
什么？
What?
哈维。
Harvey.
你到家了。  迟到总比不到好。
You're home.  Better late than never.
你为什么躲在寒冷中？
Why are you hiding out here in the cold?
我知道。对不起，我只是...
I know. I'm sorry, I just...
嗯，你开始没有我。
Mm, you started without me.
你有孩子吗？
Did you have any kids?
什么？
What?
捣蛋鬼。
Trickortreaters.
不好了。我不无。我只是...
Oh, no. I don't... no. I just...
我不认为我今晚真的受够了。
I don't think I'm really up for all that tonight.
每五分钟应门...
Answering the door every five minutes...
微笑。
Smiling.
是的，我看到门廊上的碗。
Yeah, I saw the bowl on the porch.
没关系。外面就是鬼城。
It's okay. It's a ghost town out there.
可以这么说。
So to speak.
我们要吃那个糖果一个月。
We're gonna be eating that candy for a month.
或不。
Or not.
你知道我对糖果爱恨交加。
You know I have a lovehate relationship with candy.
你对一切事物都爱恨交加。
You have a lovehate relationship with everything.
让我们爬到床上
Let's just crawl into bed
并在...上观看一部古老的黑白电影
and watch an old black and white movie on...
宝贝，我很抱歉。
Baby, I'm so sorry.
你得走了。
You have to go.
选一部电影。我很快回来。
Pick a movie. I'll be back soon.
我爱你。
I love you.
他总是让你这样等吗？
Does he always keep you waiting like this?
他会在这里。
He'll be here.
我以为你放弃了。
I thought you quit.
我有。
I have.
唔。别担心，我不会告诉芭芭拉的。
Hmm. Don't worry, I won't tell Barbara.
先生们。
Gentlemen.
啊。好的。
Ah. Good.
这是地方检察官哈维...
This is district attorney Harvey d...
蝙蝠。
Bats.
凹痕。
Dent.
好的。
Okay.
发生了什么事？
What's happened?
约翰尼·维蒂今晚被谋杀了。
Johnny viti was murdered tonight.
该死的！
Damn it!
罗马人的侄子。
The Roman's nephew.
他有名字。
He has a name.
这是胭脂红法尔科内，不是“罗马人”。
It's carmine Falcone, not "the Roman."
哈维，冷静点。
Harvey, calm down.
吉姆，你的人在哪里？我已经在 viti 上工作了几个月！
Where were your men, Jim? I've been working on viti for months!
你团队中没有人认为他会很脆弱
Nobody on your team thought he'd be vulnerable
前一天晚上他要转交州政府的证据？
the night before he's gonna turn state's evidence?
22 口径，带胶带手柄，
22 caliber, taped handle,
序列号存档。
serial number filed off.
用于消音器的婴儿奶嘴。奇怪，但有效。
Baby bottle nipple for a silencer. Odd, but effective.
且无迹可寻。
And untraceable.
很难说我们是否在与专业人士打交道。
Hard to tell if we're dealing with a professional.
当然是专业的！
Of course it was a professional!
这是法尔科内！
This was Falcone!
他发现维蒂要背叛家人，
He found out viti was gonna betray the family,
所以他把他从董事会上带走了！
so he took him off the board!
也许。
Maybe.
我们是如此接近。
We were so close.
我们是如此接近，吉姆。
We were so close, Jim.
他准备好唱歌了。
He was ready to sing.
不仅是胭脂红，全家人都要离开了。
And not just about carmine, the whole family was going away.
我们有一个真正的机会来改变事情。
We had a real opportunity to change things.
我们仍然这样做。这只是一个挫折。
We still do. It's just a setback.
我们会找到另一种方法来干掉法尔科内。
We'll find another way to take down Falcone.
一起。
Together.
杰克灯笼在哪里？
Where's the Jacko'lantern?
打扰一下？
Excuse me?
你觉得重要吗？
You think it's important?
我还不知道。
I don't know yet.
看，哈维是对的。
Look, Harvey's right.
这座城市终于有机会了。
This city's finally got a chance.
而现在站在这里的就是这三个人。
And it's the three men standing here right now.
必须取缔法尔科内犯罪家族。
The Falcone crime family has to be taken down.
所以，我把你们两个放在一起。
So, I'm putting you two together.
地方检察官 dent 将在光明中工作，而您...
District attorney dent will work in the light, and you...
会在另一边工作。
Will work the other side.
弯曲规则，但永远不要打破它们。
Bend the rules, but never break them.
我会尽我所能保护你们俩。
And I'll do everything I can to protect you both.
明白了。
Understood.
他需要听到你说出来，蝙蝠。
He needs to hear you say it, bats.
三个臭皮匠顶个诸葛亮。
Two heads are better than one.
线索来得很快。
Leads come my way pretty fast.
保持你的耳朵张开。
Keep your ears open.
然后我想我们起来了……
Then I guess we're up and...
跑步。
Running.
他经常这样做。我只是...
He does that a lot. I just...
我在自言自语。
And I'm talking to myself.
教父。
Godfather.
听到你侄子的事我很难过。
I'm so sorry to hear about your nephew.
感恩，阿米科。
Grazie, amico.
胭脂红，
Carmine,
没有不尊重
no disrespect
但为什么我们坐在我们的手上，是吗？
but why are we sitting on our hands here, huh?
他把两个放在约翰尼的头上！
He put two in Johnny's head!
谁干的？
Who did?
萨尔瓦多·马罗尼！还有谁？
Salvatore maroni! Who else?
自从他接管那个家庭以来，他就一直在为我们开枪，
Ever since he took over that family, he's been gunning for us,
今晚他找到了目标。
and tonight he found the target.
这是一个警告，为 chrissakes！
It's a warning, for chrissakes!
也许。
Perhaps.
但让我们明确一点。
But let us be clear.
扣动扳机的人没有给枪上膛。
The man who pulled the trigger did not load the gun.
Maroni 的野心受到了限制，直到法律将目标放在我的背上。
Maroni's ambition was in check until the law put a target on my back.
现在是开学季。
Now, it's open season.
如果有人要为我侄子的死负责，
If anyone is responsible for my nephew's death,
是大办公室里那个新来的婊子养的。
it's that new son of a bitch in the da's office.
凹痕。
Dent.
嗯。是的。  也许他应该和鱼一起睡。
Mmhmm. Yeah.  Maybe he should sleep with the fishes.
当然好！
Hell yes!
你只要说出这个词，胭脂红，我就会自己凹下去！
You just say the word, carmine, and I'll do dent myself!
安顿下来，安东尼。
Settle, antoni.
在适当的时候，我们会反击。直到那时...
At the right time, we'll hit back. Until then...
现在正是时候，胭脂红！
The right time is now, carmine!
现在！任何拖延只会让你看起来更虚弱！
Now! Any delay is only gonna make you look even weaker!
谢谢你的关心，安东尼。
Thank you for your concern, antoni.
没有不敬，胭脂红。
No disrespect, carmine.
是“教父”。
It's "godfather."
米洛斯。来吧！
Milos. Come on!
请！
Please!
米洛斯！不！
Milos! No!
诺尔
Nol
我们还有其他事情要讨论吗？
We have other business to discuss?
阿尔贝托？
Alberto?
阿尔贝托！
Alberto!
营业时间。
Business time.
带上你的填字游戏去散步。
Take your crosswords for a walk.
它们是……逻辑谜题。
They're... logic puzzles.
三十二继续 13。
Thirtytwo going on 13.
韦恩不会支持任何大规模的结构化工作。
Wayne is not gonna support any largescale structuring effort.
因此，就目前而言，资产必须转移到更安全的设施中。
So, for now, the assets will have to be moved to a more secure facility.
您的设备让您不堪重负。
Your equipment's weighing you down.
你为何跑？
Why are you running?
乐趣。你可以用一点乐趣。
Fun. You could use a little fun.
把你的手给我。
Give me your hand.
不。
Nah.
让你在我想要你的地方。
Got you exactly where I want you.
法尔科内。
Falcone.
沃尔特，直到你看到里面的东西。
Walt till you see what's inside.
毫米...
Mm...
你见过这样的钱吗？
Have you ever seen this kind of money?
它是正宗的。
It's authentic.
如此清爽干净。
So crisp and clean.
事实上，它非常脏。
Actually, it's incredibly dirty.
法尔科内洗钱有一段时间了。
Falcone's been having trouble laundering his cash for some time.
我们只是不知道他把它储存在哪里。
We just didn't know where he was stockpiling it.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
我很乐意提供帮助。
I'm happy to help.
为什么？
Why?
你可以把它留给自己。
You could have kept it to yourself.
有了这一切，你本可以过得很好。
You could have lived pretty well with all this.
为什么要交出来？
Why hand it over?
给你？
To you?
谁知道？
Who knows?
下来！
Get down!
从我这里拿走，伙计，
Take it from me, pal,
在这里，好奇心会让你丧命。
around here, curiosity can get you killed.
放了他。
Let him go.
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
因为他在我身边。
Because he's with me.
另外，因为他是将你所有的朋友都投入阿卡姆的达人。
Also, because he's the da who put all your friends into arkham.
我们还有一个空间。
We got room for one more.
有人关注我们吗？
Anyone follow us?
我几乎跟不上我们。
I could barely follow us.
猎鹰进口一直在做着相当大的生意。
Falcone imports has been doing quite a business.
你知道，如果我们是其他男人……
You know, if we were any other men...
不是。
We're not.
是的。不。当然。
Yeah. No. Of course.
所以现在怎么办？
So, what now?
我们应该打电话给戈登。
We should call Gordon.
让他的手下捡起来作为证据。
Have his men pick this up as evidence.
法尔科内拥有市长和整个市议会。
Falcone owns the mayor and the entire city assembly.
明天它就会回到他的金库里。
It'd be back in his coffers by tomorrow.
因此，产生影响的唯一方法就是让它消失。
So, the only way to make an impact is to make it disappear.
是的，但看看这一切。搬家可能需要几天时间。
Yeah, but look at all this. Moving it could take days.
好吧，谁说搬家了？
Well, who said anything about moving it?
你为什么要伤害法尔科内？
Why are you trying to hurt Falcone?
你为什么？
Why are you?
这不是个人的，亲爱的。这是正义。
It's not personal, sweetheart. It's justice.
正义可以是个人的，亲爱的。
Justice can be personal, sweetie.
给我一个先机。
Give me a head start.
我不想在这里附近的任何地方被抓到。
I don't want to get caught anywhere near here.
我不知道。
I don't know.
戈登说我应该在灯光下工作。
Gordon says I'm supposed to work in the light.
那么，点亮吧。
Well, then, light it up.
我欠你一个人情。
I owe you one.
你欠我的，就像……
You owe me, like...
十亿。
A billionfive.
我真的不能既是律师又是罪犯，对吗？
I can't really be a lawyer and a criminal, can I?
我要赢。
I want to win.
但我想这样赢吗？
But do I want to win like this?
我在这里有两种想法。
I'm of two minds here.
所以，这是一个抛硬币。
So, it's a coin flip.
是的，我想是的。
Yeah, I guess it is.
头，我们烧掉它。
Heads, we burn it down.
好的。
Okay.
打电话给陈。
Call chen.
消防队员在工业区现场
Firefighters on the scene here in the industrial district
努力控制火焰
working to contain the Blaze
在它蔓延到附近的家庭和企业之前。
before it can spread to nearby homes and businesses.
现在，在这个时候，杰基，
Now, at this time, Jackie,
官员认为，Falcone 进口仓库，
officials believe the Falcone imports warehouse,
当然，由臭名昭著的法尔科内犯罪家族拥有，
owned, of course, by the notorious Falcone crime family,
有空……
to be vacant...
“三个臭皮匠顶个诸葛亮。”
"Two heads are better than one."
吉尔达？
Gilda?
嘿！你吓到我了。
Hey! You scared me.
我回到家，我不知道你在哪里。
I came home and I didn't know where you were.
你听到我的呼唤了吗？
Did you hear me calling?
请留下。
Please stay.
我哪儿也不去。
I'm not going anywhere.
我是认真的。不要离开我。
I mean it. Don't leave me.
宝贝，我知道我没去过。我很抱歉。
Baby, I know I haven't been around. And I'm sorry.
但是这份工作...
But this job...
这不是永远。
It isn't forever.
嘿，我们今晚在这个法尔科内的事情上有了很大的突破。
Hey, we caught a huge break tonight on this Falcone thing.
一旦我带他出去，我就会带他出去，
Once I take him out, and I will take him out,
事情会有所不同。
things are gonna be different.
我们可以组建一个家庭。
We can start a family.
你知道我不能。
You know I can't.
当然可以。我们可以。
Of course you can. We can.
当您准备好时，我们将讨论选项，
We'll talk about options when you're ready,
但我需要你相信我们仍然在正轨上。
but I need you to trust that we're still on track.
还有我爱你。
And that I love you.
现在，我们还有电影之夜吗？
Now, are we still having movie night, or not?
不，甚至不要回答那个。来吧。
No, don't even answer that. Come on.
如果我们走第66路，我们可以在西桥切断他们。
If we take 66th, we can cut them off at the westward bridge.
不。暂时保持安全距离。
No. Maintain a safe distance for now.
晚上好，先生。火鸡在烤，
Good evening, sir. The Turkey is roasting,
馅饼正在冷却，凯尔小姐正在路上。
the pies are cooling, and miss Kyle is en route.
阿尔弗雷德，记下订购一个新的挡风玻璃。
Alfred, make a note to order a new windshield.
防弹。
Bulletproof.
当然，先生，但如果我可以...
Of course, sir, but if I may...
啊！
Aah!
我还以为你没有伤害人呢！
I thought you didn't hurt people!
你想错了。
You thought wrong.
你和你的三好会哥们
You and your San ho hui buddies
万圣节那天在哈维·丹特的房子外面被人看到。
were seen outside Harvey dent's house on Halloween.
我们在耍花招。
We were trickortreating.
正玩得开心？
Having fun?
还没有。
Not yet.
但现在任何时候。
But any second now.
是的！
Yeah!
去。我会留意你的小伙伴们。
Go. I'll keep an eye on your little friends.
一句“谢谢”就好了！
A "thank you" would be nice!
这是感恩节。
It is Thanksgiving.
我们可以让这一切变得简单，米奇。
We can make this easy, Mickey.
告诉我谁雇你杀丹特。
Just tell me who hired you to kill dent.
去地狱吧，蝙蝠怪！
Go to hell, batfreak!
此刻，你我的唯一区别
Right now, the only difference between you and me
是我知道这里有什么。
is that I know what's down here.
唔。
Hmm.
咕噜咕噜。
Grundy.
他是我的。
He's mine.
放了他。
Let him go.
这是你的地方。
This is your place.
把他交给我，我会确保他再也不会踏足这里。
Give him to me and I'll make sure he never sets foot down here again.
你可以一个人。
You can be alone.
星期一出生。
Born on a Monday.
再给你一份。
One more for ya.
我的天啊。
My goodness.
哦，这不是给你丈夫的。这是给你的。
Oh, this one's not for your husband. It's for you.
来自“法尔科内先生”。
From a "Mr. Falcone."
对不起，女士。
I'm sorry, ma'am.
不关我的事...
It's none of my business...
不是他的晚餐时间吗？
Isn't it time for his dinner?
我不想在这里，米克。
I don't wanna be here, Mick.
我妻子正在用所有的辅料烹饪火鸡。
My wife's cooking Turkey with all the trimmings.
我喜欢土耳其的所有装饰。
I love Turkey with all the trimmings.
所以，告诉我们你所知道的
So, just tell us what you know
关于地方检察官家里的炸弹，
about the bomb in the district attorney's house,
那我们都可以去吃饭了。
then we can all go eat.
我什至不知道胭脂红法尔科内。
I don't even know carmine Falcone.
罗马人承包了你的黑社会来消灭哈维凹痕！
The Roman contracted your triad to take out Harvey dent!
你的签名无处不在。
Your signature's all over it.
米奇，你得帮我让我的朋友保持冷静。
Mickey, you gotta help me keep my friend here calm.
给我们一些东西...
Just give us something...
任何事物。
Anything.
有人想陷害我。
Someone's trying to frame me.
我告诉你了。我是无辜的。
I told you. I'm innocent.
椅子是给嫌疑人的。
Chairs are for suspects.
这人是无辜的。
This guy's innocent.
哇哇哇哇哇哇！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
嘿。我以为我们只是在做一件事。
Hey. I thought we were just doing a thing.
如果这家伙受伤，这个小动作不会让我们有任何进展。
This little act doesn't get us anywhere if the guy gets hurt.
也许你们应该承认你对三好会一无所知。
Maybe you guys should admit you have nothing on San ho hui.
如果你有，你早就预定了我。
If you had, you would've booked me already.
好的。就是这样。蒙托亚！
All right. That's it. Montoya!
请让我们的朋友出去。
Please, show our friend out.
也许你应该感谢那个埋下炸弹的人。
Maybe you should thank whoever planted that bomb.
你说什么？
What did you say?
你还没有弄清楚是谁杀死了约翰尼·维蒂？
You still haven't figured out who killed Johnny viti?
让他离开我的视线。
Get him outta my sight.
你可能是打架的王牌，
You may be aces in a fistfight,
但是你有很多关于侦探工作的东西要学。
but you've got a lot to learn about detective work.
我找到了他，不是吗？
I found him, didn't I?
这不仅仅是找到它们。
It's not just about finding them.
你必须知道他们将如何帮助你的案子。
You gotta know how they're gonna help your case.
Mickey chen是Falcone保护的一条小鱼。
Mickey chen is a small fish protected by Falcone.
我们永远不会得到坦白。
We were never going to get a confession.
我们需要结交朋友，并及时翻转他。
We needed to make friends and, in time, flip him.
继续这样说话，他们会让你大吃一惊。
Keep talking like that, they'll make you da.
哈维还没有死。
Harvey isn't dead yet.
而且他也不是杀手。
And he isn't a killer, either.
不管那个渣男怎么想。
No matter what that scumbag thinks.
他甚至从未拥有过枪。
He's never even owned a gun.
法尔康适合。
Falcone fits.
罗马人杀死了维蒂并下令击中凹痕。
The Roman killed viti and ordered the hit on dent.
奥卡姆剃刀。
Occam's razor.
最简单的解释通常是正确的。
The simplest explanation is usually the right one.
好的。如果我现在离开，我可能只是做晚饭。
All right. If I leave now, I might just make dinner.
你也应该和你的人在一起。
You should be with your people, too.
美好的。
Fine.
晚安。
Good night.
感恩节快乐，邓太太。
Happy Thanksgiving, Mrs. dent.
现在，我敢肯定这位小姐快要出去买些真正的食物了，
Now, I'm sure the missus is running out to pick up some real food,
但我向你保证，你从来没有吃过南瓜派……
but I guarantee you, you have never had pumpkin pie like...
呃，登特先生？
Uh, Mr. dent?
我只是，你知道，想离开这座城市，我讨厌这个地方。
I just, you know, wanna get out of the city, I hate this place.
好的。
Nice.
秘密是罗勒。
The secret is the basil.
你只想要最年轻的植物最年轻的叶子，
You want only the youngest leaves from the youngest plant,
否则，就像薄荷一样。
otherwise, it's like mint.
压倒一切。
Overpowers everything.
我们要感谢很多，阿尔贝托。
We have a lot to be thankful for, Alberto.
如？
Such as?
健康。家庭。
Health. Family.
还剩下什么。
What's left of it.
如果你指的是你的堂兄约翰尼，
If you are referring to your cousin Johnny,
正在处理中。
that is being handled.
米奇陈。
By Mickey chen.
你认为谁雇佣了他？
And who do you think hired him?
当然。
Of course.
你有什么想说的吗？
Is there something you wish to say?
不，爸爸。
No, poppa.
除了指出Harvey dent还活着。
Except to point out that Harvey dent is still alive.
因为我允许。
Because I allow it.
目前。
For now.
这...
This...
这就是我一直在谈论的。
This is what I keep talking about.
这是牛津。
This is Oxford.
那个地方污染了你的思想，阿尔贝托。
That place polluted your mind, Alberto.
你曾经知道你的地方。现在？
You used to know your place. Now?
我不应该把你送到那里。
I should have never sent you there.
独立思考的危险。
The dangers of independent thought.
你什么时候有过独立的想法
When have you had one independent thought
居然让这个家庭受益？
that actually benefited this family?
也许当我送花到 dent 的病房时
Maybe when I sent flowers to dent's hospital room
在法尔科内的名字。
in the Falcone name.
你做了什么？
You did what?
我送花。
I sent flowers.
我以为这会消除我们的怀疑
I thought it would take suspicion off of us
如果我们看起来像我们关心他的康复。
if we looked like we care about his recovery.
现在，我想你会说这是一个草率的举动。
Now, I suppose you'll say it was a sloppy move.
我可以原谅草率。
I can forgive sloppy.
我所不能容忍的，
What I will not tolerate,
你是想代表这个家庭发言吗？
is you presuming to speak on behalf of this family.
让我说清楚。
Let me be perfectly clear.
再次。
Again.
您可能持有的关于排在下一位的任何想法
Any notion you may hold about being next in line
接管我们的商业利益
to take over our business interests
是可悲的妄想。
is a pathetic delusion.
你太弱了。
You are weak.
你的软弱是我的责任。
Your weakness is my liability.
你必须与 Harvey dent 先生或夫人零接触。
You are to have zero contact with Mr. or Mrs. Harvey dent.
讨论完毕。
End of discussion.
哈维！
Harvey!
你好。
Hello.
我接到一个电话，说你在医院失踪了。
I got a call that you went missing from the hospital.
我怎么知道我会在这里找到你？
How did I know I'd find you here?
再也受不了被关起来了。
Couldn't stand being cooped up anymore.
以为我会伸展我的腿。
Thought I'd stretch my legs.
是的。
Yeah.
听着，你为什么不跳进去？我带你回去。
Listen, why don't you hop in? I'll take you back.
不好了。不不不不，我喜欢这里。
Oh, no. No. No. No. No. I like it out here.
我正在回家吃感恩节晚餐的路上。
I'm on my way home for Thanksgiving dinner.
你应该一起来。芭芭拉总是赚很多。
You should come along. Barbara always makes a ton.
我不饿。
I'm not hungry.
哈维，我们在这里做什么？
Harvey, what are we doing here?
我不知道。也许我还没有准备好。
I don't know. Maybe I wasn't ready for this yet.
我想我现在要回去了。
I think I'm gonna go back now.
你不用担心哈维。
Don't you worry about Harvey.
好的，辅导员。
All right, counselor.
就我而言，你没有这个。
As far as I'm concerned, you don't have this.
猎鹰是危险的人，对他们来说，你是坏人。
The falcones are dangerous people and, to them, you're the bad guy.
保护你的家人。
Protect your family.
所以，我向他提出了一个提议，你知道。
So, I made him an offer, you know.
给家人。
To the family.
那些亲爱的离去...
Those dearly departed...
还有那些我们今天有幸在我们身边的人。
And those whom we are fortunate to have beside us here today.
让我们感谢我们还在一起的时光
Let us be thankful for the time we still have together
以及赐予我们的许多祝福。
and for the many blessings bestowed upon us.
阿拉致敬！  礼炮！
Alla salute!  Salute!
是的。
Ah, yes.
哦，看。  哦，过来！
Oh, look.  Oh, come here!
哦哦！  是的！
Ohho!  Yeah!
我告诉过你我会走路。  非常好。非常好。
I told you I'd walk.  Very good. Very good.
是的！
Yeah!
\哇哦！
\wwhoohoo!
欢迎回来。
Welcome back.
芭芭拉？
Barbara?
哦！
Ooh!
所罗门...
Solomon grundy...
星期一出生...
Born on a Monday...
相信我，我告诉他他可以把斗篷粘在哪里。
Believe me, I told him where he could stick the cape.
连戈登都笑了。
Even Gordon laughed.
那时他们才放我走。
That's when they let me go.
你不需要我做这个。我应该出去打猎。
You don't need me for this. I should be out hunting.
我们已经涵盖了它。
We've got it covered.
到午夜时分，Gotham 的所有警局都将部署到整个城镇。
All of Gotham pd will be deployed throughout town by midnight.
无论如何，当假期来临时，我们会做好准备。
One way or another, when holiday comes calling, we'll be ready.
你知道，这就是你的全部。
You know, this was all you.
我希望他们在哥谭监狱。
I wanted them in Gotham penitentiary.
这是哈维。他是对的。
This was Harvey. And he was right.
日历人。
Calendar man.
所以...
So...
只在假期工作的杀手。
A killer who only works on holidays.
现在是 12 月 24 日。
And it's December 24th.
我想知道你什么时候来找我。
I was wondering when you'd get to me.
我们没有太多时间，一天。
We don't have much time, day.
谁在万圣节杀死了约翰尼维蒂？
Who killed Johnny viti on Halloween?
在感恩节杀死陈米奇和他的船员的同一个人。
The same person who killed Mickey chen and his crew on Thanksgiving.
我们需要一个比这更好的答案。
We need a better answer than that.
维蒂是罗马人的侄子。
Viti was the Roman's nephew.
罗马人是陈的雇主。
The Roman was chen's employer.
因此，第一个嫌疑人是
First suspect is, therefore,
罗马人。
the Roman.
但既然偷偷摸摸不是法尔科内的风格，
But since sneaking around isn't really Falcone's style,
我们继续讨论第二个嫌疑人。
we move on to the second suspect.
有人希望罗马帝国灭亡。
Someone hoping for the fall of the Roman empire.
就像萨尔马罗尼一样。
Like sal maroni.
他和其他人一样善于猜测。
He's as good a guess as any of the others.
什么“别人”？
What "others"?
你是一个男人。
You're down a man.
这是浪费时间。
This is a waste of time.
我告诉过你带丹特先生来。
I told you to bring Mr. dent.
他在外面不安全。
He isn't safe out there.
那个把你们都关进阿卡姆的达人？
The da who put you all in arkham?
这里有一半的病人会一见他就杀了他，
Half the patients here would kill him on sight,
所以，我想说外面是他唯一安全的地方。
so, I'd say out there is the only place he is safe.
也许。
Perhaps.
或者他不知道你在这里。
Or perhaps he doesn't know you're here.
也许...
Perhaps...
地方检察官...
The district attorney...
是嫌疑人。
Is a suspect.
啊。
Ah.
嗯，当然。智能、计算、
Well, of course. Intelligent, calculating,
任务是取下胭脂红法尔科内。
with a mission to take down carmine Falcone.
这一切都合适。
It all fits.
Harvey dent 不是杀手。
Harvey dent is not a killer.
除非他过着双重生活。
Unless he's leading a double life.
就像你的斗篷十字军，在这里。
Like your caped crusader, here.
你为什么要找我？
Why did you ask for me?
所以你可以自己看看。
So you could see for yourself.
我没有时间让你发疯。
I don't have time for your crazy.
你真的没有。
You really don't.
这几天有很多疯子。
There's lots of crazy out there these days.
就在你以为你已经把它全部清理干净的时候。
And just when you thought you'd cleaned it all up.
什么...
What a...
玩笑。
Joke.
节日快乐。
Happy holiday.
打开它！
Open it!
他让别人来找我的孩子！
He had somebody get to my kid!
如果……如果我没有帮助他。
If... if I didn't help him.
抱歉。
I'm sorry.
哈维不安全。
Harvey isn't safe.
去！
Go!
“这是一个欢乐的季节
"Tis the season to be jolly
哈哈哈哈哈！哈哈哈哈！
hahahahaha! Hahahaha!
外面是一个可怕的冷却器
Outside it's an awful chiller
哈哈哈哈哈！哈哈哈哈！
hahahahaha! Hahahaha!
男孩，这个假期是个杀手
Boy, this holiday's a killer
哈哈哈哈哈！哈哈哈哈！
hahahahaha! Hahahaha!
吉尔达？那是你吗？
Gilda? Is that you?
“吉尔达”！
"Gilda"!
她看起来像吉尔达。
She looked like a gilda.
放松，棒棒糖！
Relax, lollipop!
警察问题。
Police issue.
我的妻子在哪里？
Where's my wife?
她就在我离开她的地方，最后一刻购物。
She's just where I left her, lastminute shopping.
剧透警报。是袜子。
Spoiler alert. It's socks.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
哇，我以为我在玩圣诞老人！
Aww, I thought I was playing santi claus!
哦那好吧。
Oh, all right.
我想要一辆消防车和一个足球……
I want a fire engine and a football and...
传递消息。
To deliver a message.
放下枪，我们再谈。
Put the gun down and we'll talk.
当然！
Sure!
你的怀疑是正确的。
Your suspicions were correct.
据报道，一名圣诞老人小丑今天恐吓了三个家庭。
A Santa clown has reportedly terrorized three families today.
先生，他们都被命名为“凹痕”。
Sir, they were all named "dent."
哇！
Whoo!
你是在哪里拿到的？
Where did you get that?
为什么？
Why?
雅想念一个？
Ya missin' one?
你可以用一些振作起来！
You could use some cheering up!
你听说过那个关于杀人小丑的吗？
Have ya heard the one about the murderous clown
逃出庇护所的
that escaped the asylum
并出现在把他放在那里的那个人的家里？
and showed up at the home of the da who put him there?
看，围绕这些部分一直有谣言
See, there's a persistent rumor round these parts
那个大凹痕比他看起来的要多。
that da dent is more than he appears to be.
但是这个镇上只容得下一个杀人狂。
But there's only room for one homicidal maniac in this town.
如果我听到快乐的 Harvey dent 离开了，
And if I hear that happy Harvey dent is steppin' out,
我会确保小吉尔达不用去服装店
I'll make sure little gilda doesn't have to clothesshop
再次为哈比乌比。
for hubbywubby ever again.
你说这是笑话？
You call that a joke?
但你甚至没有听到妙语！
But you haven't even heard the punchline!
它是这样的！
It goes like this!
哈维。
Harvey.
哈维，你能听到我说话吗？
Harvey, can you hear me?
知道他要去哪里吗？
Any idea where he was heading?
马罗尼...
Maroni...
曼吉亚。
Mangia.
你朋友的脸怎么了，马罗尼？
What happened to your friend's face, maroni?
没什么。你的怎么了？
Nothin'. What happened to yours?
哦，你妈……
Oh, you mother...
告诉我他说的一切。
Tell me everything he said.
如果你离开我的脖子。
If you get off of my neck.
在我们到达那里之前，他已经在里面了。
He was inside before we got there.
干掉整个工作人员，毒死了fagioli。
Took out the whole staff, poisoned the fagioli.
我不饿，但是，呃，弗雷迪，这里……
I wasn't hungry, but, uh, Freddy, here...
我不知道。猜猜我很幸运。
I don't know. Guess I'm lucky.
不，他让你活了。为什么？
No. He let you live. Why?
我看起来像我知道吗？
Do I look like I know?
他用枪指着我的脸告诉我这是他的地盘
He put a gun in my face and told me that this is his turf
并且他正在打击闯入者。
and that he's cracking down on interlopers.
也许我应该感谢他。
Maybe I should thank him.
我不知道你在哪里下车。
I don't know where you get off.
像这个小丑这样的怪胎过去常常在边缘玩耍，
Freaks like this clown used to play way out on the fringe,
但是一旦你出现...
but once you showed up...
放轻松，伙计。
Relax, pal.
你知道，过去在这个镇上一切都很顺利。
Ya know, things used to run smooth in this town.
现在，我们有杀手鳄鱼、飞蛾和下水道僵尸，
Now, we got killer crocs and moths and sewer zombies,
更何况是个杀人狂
not to mention a homicidal maniac
在假期里偷偷摸摸地制造男人。
skulking around the holidays hittin' made men.
共同点是什么？呵呵。
What's the common thread? Huh.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
谁知道？他是个疯子。
Who knows? He's a nutjob.
但如果他是杀死法尔科内手下的人，
But if he's the guy killin' Falcone's men,
他自己变成老胭脂只是时间问题。
it's only a matter of time till he gets to old carmine himself.
也许从那里开始。
Maybe start there.
不是真正的侦探，是吗？
Not really much of a detective, are ya?
你好。
Hello.
海军，海军，木炭，黑色。
Navy, Navy, charcoal, black.
啊!
Ugh!
真的，卡姆，一抹颜色是不是太过分了？
Really, carm, is a splash of color too much to ask?
别胡闹了。如果你要杀了我，就去做吧。
Stop clowning around. If you're gonna kill me, just do it.
这是杀手的脸吗？
Is this the face of a killer?
啊!
Ugh!
我猜是！
I guess it is!
哦，放松点，polpetto，我不会杀了你。
Oh, relax, polpetto, I'm not going to kill you.
反正今晚不行。
Not tonight, anyway.
圣诞节了！
It's Christmas!
但...
But...
今晚会有人死去。
Someone will die tonight.
可能是你身边的某个人。
Probably someone close to you.
你不想知道谁在扣动扳机吗？
Don't you want to know who's pulling the trigger?
Anyhoo，我只是突然说，
Anyhoo, I just popped in to say,
如果您听到有关假期调查的任何消息，
if you hear any news about the holiday investigation,
我希望你通过我的方式。
I'd like you to pass it my way.
作为职业礼节。
As a professional courtesy.
这是我的卡！
Here's my card!
邦纳塔莱！
Buon natale!
邦纳塔莱。
Buon natale.
呼！
Hoo!
我杀了我。
I kill me.
我勒个去？
What the hell?
想念我！
Missed me!
哇！
Whoo!
你知道我忘记了什么吗？
You know what I forgot?
哇！那很接近了。
Whoa! That was close.
车轮
Wheel
我会提醒你，先生，
I would remind you, sir,
Falcone 先生为 Gotham 儿童诊所提供的年度福利。
of Mr. Falcone's annual benefit for the Gotham children's clinic.
建议至少露脸一年。
It would be advisable to show your face at least one year.
你父亲建了那家医院。
Your father built that hospital.
他帮助罗马人建造了它。
He helped the Roman build it.
仍然是一个很好的理由。
Still, a good cause.
而且，坦率地说，在游艇上度过一晚可能对您有好处。
And, frankly, a night on a yacht could do you some good.
凯尔小姐会在那里。
Miss Kyle will be there.
三个假期发生了三起谋杀案。
Three murders on three holidays.
每个受害者都是法尔科内的同事。
Each of the victims a Falcone associate.
所有人都用相同类型的无法追踪的枪射击。
All shot with the same type of untraceable gun.
没有天分。
No withesses.
嫌疑人？
Suspects?
萨尔瓦多·马罗尼。
Salvatore maroni.
他的家族总是仅次于罗马人。
His family's always been second to the Roman.
他是出了名的野心勃勃。
He's notoriously ambitious.
但他在光天化日之下杀死了法尔科内的手下。
But he's killed Falcone's men in broad daylight.
为什么是 cloakanddagger 假期业务？
Why the cloakanddagger holiday business?
卡拉·维蒂，法尔科内的妹妹。
Carla viti, Falcone's sister.
经营他们的芝加哥业务。
Runs their Chicago operation.
她可能是为了控制家庭而做戏。
She could be making a play for control of the family.
在万圣节杀死她唯一的儿子？
By killing her only son on Halloween?
她是个罪犯。
She is a criminal.
而且他是个杀人狂。
And he is a homicidal maniac.
守卫作证说他在第一次谋杀之前逃跑了。
The guard testified that he escaped before the first murder.
罗马人本人。
The Roman himself.
Johnny viti 快要翻身了
Johnny viti was about to flip
陈米奇可以作证说法尔科内下令谋杀丹特。
and Mickey chen could testify that Falcone ordered dent's murder.
他有动机让他们俩都闭嘴。
He had motive to silence them both.
但是为什么要杀自己的保镖呢？
But why kill his own bodyguard?
请问你为什么要让第五名嫌疑人离开董事会？
May I ask why you're keeping the fifth suspect off the board?
因为我不喜欢。
Because I don't like it.
但它适合。不是吗？
But it fits. Doesn't it?
痴迷于取下法尔科内。
Obsessed with taking down Falcone.
不仅仅是老板马罗尼和镇上每一个雄心勃勃的男人。
More than boss maroni and every ambitious made man in town.
去年他的持枪执照被拒绝了，
He was turned down for a gun license last year,
当心理评估显示出一些疯狂的畸变时。
when the psych eval showed some wild aberrations.
或者完全是别人？
Or is it someone else entirely?
我们甚至没有考虑过的人。
Someone we haven't even considered.
我以为这是为了扫街上的罪犯，
I thought this would be about sweeping criminals off the street,
也许直接吓到他们。
maybe scaring them straight.
我从没想过蝙蝠侠会成为一名侦探。
I never thought that Batman was going to have to be a detective.
一个很好的。
A good one.
如果我救不了他们怎么办，阿尔弗雷德？
What if I can't save them, Alfred?
我以前见过这些成长的痛苦，先生，
I've seen these growing pains before, sir,
我相信，最终，
and I am confident that, in the end,
蝙蝠侠将成为世界需要他成为的样子。
the Batman will be what the world needs him to be.
我相信，布鲁斯韦恩也应该如此。
The same, I believe, should be said of Bruce Wayne.
我尊贵的客人，
My distinguished guests,
我很荣幸今晚在这里欢迎你。
it is my honor to welcome you here tonight.
我看到很多熟悉的面孔。市长。
I see a lot of familiar faces. Mayor.
阁下。
Your eminence.
不，我是在和萨尔马罗尼说话。
No, I was talking to sal maroni.
萨尔马罗尼。在我的游艇上。
Sal maroni. On my yacht.
就像我父亲常说的，“让你的敌人靠近...
It's like my father always said, "keep your enemies close...
还有一把上膛的枪靠近。”
And a loaded gun closer."
扬。
Yeanh.
三十年前，一小群忧心忡忡的哥谭人
Thirty years ago, a small group of concerned gothamites
联合起来建造某物
joined together to build something
在政府大厅里争吵的政客们不能。
the politicians squabbling in the halls of government could not.
托马斯韦恩博士和我
Dr. Thomas Wayne and I
建立儿童诊所以保护家庭。
built the children's clinic to protect families.
如果你认识我，
And if you know me,
你知道对我来说没有什么比家人更重要的了。
you know there is nothing more important to me than family.
所以，buon anno！
So, buon anno!
感谢大家来到这里，感谢你们的慷慨。
Thank you all for being here and for your generosity.
让我们击败去年的总数。
Let's beat last year's total.
请记住，请只收现金。
Remember, cash only, please.
另外，我要感谢我们的企业赞助商，
Also, I would like to thank our corporate sponsors,
科德万能，
kord omniversal,
苏打可乐，
soder cola,
并且，连续 10 年，Gotham 广播公司。
and, for the 10th year running, Gotham broadcasting company.
哦！上。
Oh! On.
我很抱歉！
I'm so sorry!
来，让我。
Here, let me.
不，谢谢。
No, thank you.
还有一件事，然后我保证我会让你享受派对。
One more thing, and then I promise I'll let you enjoy the party.
我想承认一个人。
I would like to acknowledge someone.
正如我所说，对我来说，没有什么比家人更重要。
As I said, nothing is more important to me than family.
而且，也许，我的一个遗憾
And, perhaps, my one regret
让这个男人觉得他不是这个家庭的一员。
is making this man feel like he is not a part of this family.
我们并不总是就细节达成一致。
We have not always agreed on details.
但我们在最重要的事情上意见一致。
But we agree on the most important things.
我们相信家庭。
We believe in family.
我们相信商业。
We believe in business.
而且，就像今晚在座的所有人一样，
And, like all of you here tonight,
我们相信哥谭市。
we believe in Gotham city.
女士们先生们，我从未有过的儿子……
Ladies and gentlemen, the son I never had...
布鲁斯韦恩先生。
Mr. Bruce Wayne.
我想我看到他们了！  什么？
I think I see them!  Whwhat?
好像很重要似的。反正我几乎见不到你。
As if it matters. I hardly ever see you, anyway.
我只想说，没必要...
I'm just saying, there's no need to...
嘿，哈维！
Hey, Harvey!
你不应该工作吗，船长？
Shouldn't you be working, captain?
我是。
I am.
这是这座城市有史以来规模最大的警察存在。
This is the largest police presence this city's ever seen.
我们在圣诞节被抓到裤子掉了，
We got caught with our pants down on Christmas,
但是如果他今晚在这里尝试任何事情，天堂会帮助他度过假期。
but heaven help holiday if he tries anything here tonight.
一直在值班。
Always on duty.
总是。
Always.
你没带孩子？
You didn't bring the kids?
他们今晚要在我妈妈那里过夜。
They're sleeping over at my mother's tonight.
下次我们应该试着雇你坐下，吉尔达。
We should try and hire you to sit next time, gilda.
我敢打赌你对孩子很好。
I bet you're great with kids.
我已经很多年没有当保姆了。
I haven't worked as a sitter in years.
它支付了她通过法学院的费用。
It paid her way through law school.
我不知道你是律师。
I didn't know you're a lawyer.
我曾是。
I was.
现在，我什么都不是。
Now, I'm not anything.
飞行员死了？查看。
Dead pilot? Check.
地勤人员？查看。
Ground crew? Check.
毒气？查看。
Poison gas? Check.
是时候敲响新的一年了。
Time to ring in the new year.
女士们，先生们，请系好安全带，
Ladies and gentlemen, please fasten your seatbelts,
因为我不知道如何飞行这个东西！
as I have no idea how to fly this thing!
看起来像一个真正的派对。
Looks like a real party.
那么，我们到底在这里做什么？
So, what the hell are we doing here?
我不知道。
I don't know.
有人告诉我这是我今晚需要去的地方。
Something tells me this is where I need to be tonight.
我们...
We...
看，我们还没有谈过，我想我们应该。
Look, we haven't talked, and I think we should.
我觉得不管这是什么...
I feel like whatever this is...
无论我们试图成为彼此的什么……都在瓦解。
Whatever we've tried to be to one another is... unraveling.
我们都知道为什么。
And we both know why.
我们从来没有说过，
We've never spoken of it,
但事实是，你和我是两个不同的人。
but the truth is that you and I are two different people.
尝试很有趣...
It was fun to try...
但我认为我们永远不可能把它们放在一起。
But I don't think we're ever gonna be able to put it all together.
我想我们只是不适合...
I guess we're just not cut out for...
不管这是什么。
Whatever this is.
曾是。
Was.
不过不用担心。我会在另一边见到你。
Don't worry, though. I'll see you on the other side.
你什么时候做的？
When did you do it?
做什么？
Do what?
你在我没有注意到的情况下拿走了我的手表。
You took my watch without me noticing.
那么，你什么时候做的？我很好奇。
So, when did you do it? I'm curious.
从我这里拿走，布鲁斯，
Take it from me, Bruce,
在这里，好奇心会让你丧命。
around here, curiosity can get you killed.
现在不要。
Not now.
什么？
What?
在哪里？
Where?
我只想过一个正常的夜晚。我们可以过一个正常的夜晚吗？
I just want to have a normal night. Can we just have a normal night?
我什至不知道那是什么了。
I don't even know what that is anymore.
我一个人在这里。
I am alone here.
我告诉自己没关系，因为它会变得更好，
I told myself it was okay because it would get better,
但它没有。
but it hasn't.
你不必独自一人。
You don't have to be alone.
我们已经谈过要生孩子了。
We've talked about having a baby.
我不能！你知道我不能！
I can't! You know that I can't!
也许不是老式的方式，
Maybe not the oldfashioned way,
但这并不意味着我们不能尝试一些东西......
but that doesn't mean that we can't try something...
我不要。
I don't want it.
我不想要，因为我不能，我不能，因为我不想要。
I don't want it because I can't and I can't because I don't want it.
我们可以私下谈谈这个吗？
Can we please talk about this in private?
耶稣，你为什么不能更像……
Jesus, why can't you be more like...
更像谁？
More like who?
我只是一个人。
I'm only one man.
我不能这样做。
I can't do this.
现在不要。
Not now.
原谅我们。
Excuse us.
吉姆，你知道他们有这些问题吗？
Jim, did you know they're having these kinds of problems?
吉姆？
Jim?
是的。我现在看到了。
Yeah. I see it now.
嗯？
Huh?
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
糟糕的新年！
Crappy new year!
嘿。
Hey.
如果所有的罪行都被遗忘并且永远不会受到审判......
Should all offenses be forgot and never brought to trial...
哦，愚蠢的我。安全。哈！
Oh, silly me. The safety. Ha!
哦，漂亮。
Ooh, pretty.
嗯？
Huh?
好吧，该死。
Well, shit.
经济舱不是她以前的样子。哈！
Economy class ain't what she used to be. Ha!
这个区域需要明确！
This area needs to be clear!
每个人都保持冷静。
Everyone remain calm.
这条路！
This way!
皮尔斯！  船长，先生！
Pearce!  Captain, sir!
我需要让我的妻子离开这里。
I need to get my wife out of here.
是的先生！跟着我，女士。
Yes, sir! Follow me, ma'am.
你想用这个噱头证明什么，小丑？
What are you trying to prove with this stunt, joker?
证明？特技？小丑？
Prove? Stunt? Joker?
不，等等，那个是对的。
No, wait, that one's right.
你为什么要杀约翰尼·维蒂？？什么？
Why did you kill Johnny viti? ?What?
还有米奇陈和米洛斯格拉巴酒？
And Mickey chen and milos grappa?
你以为我在放假？
You think I'm holiday?
哦，poppet，我不知道你在乎。
Oh, poppet, I didn't know you cared.
我当然不是假期！
Of course I'm not holiday!
如果我是他，我为什么要试图杀死他？
If I were him, why would I be trying to kill him?
杀了他？
Kill him?
他是竞争对手！
He's the competition!
而且，就像玉米粒常说的那样，
And, like the corn kernel always says,
“我不会是第二。”
"I won't be number two."
如果是假期你想死...
If it's holiday you want dead...
那为什么要在哥谭广场给大家加油呢？
Then why gas everyone in Gotham square?
半个城市都在那里，
Half the city's down there,
这意味着假期要么是，要么不是！
which means holiday either is, or isn't!
我有5050的机会。
I have a 5050 chance.
如果我失败了，至少我杀了很多无辜的人。
And if I fail, well, at least I've killed a lot of innocent people.
不，别杀我！在我发现谁是假期之前！
No, don't kill me! Not before I find out who holiday is!
你为什么在乎？
Why do you care?
哦，你这个可爱的傻瓜！
Oh, you adorable fool!
你现在不知道吗？我和你一样！
Don't you know by now? I'm just like youl!
我们都喜欢一个好的拼图。
We both love a good puzzle.
所以，当时钟敲响 12:00 时，
So, when the clock strikes 12:00,
我得到一个小吻吗？
do I get a little kiss?
哎呀！将其视为“不”。
Whoop! Taking that as a "no."
这是我的决心。
There goes my resolution.
哈尔
Hal
挡道。现在！移动！
out of the way. Now! Move!
阿尔贝托，对吧？
Alberto, right?
赛琳娜。
Selina.
我可以问你一个问题吗？
Can I ask you a question?
我试图想象在这一切周围长大是什么感觉。
I'm trying to imagine what it's like to grow up around all this.
我不会知道。
I wouldn't know.
“家人先生”让我在我走路之前就在国外寄宿学校。
"Mr. family" had me in boarding schools overseas before I could walk.
这很好。无论如何，我永远不会适应这里。
Which is fine. I would have never fit in here, anyway.
我是牛津大学的毕业生，对商业有了更多的了解
I'm an Oxford graduate who's learned more about business
比我父亲希望理解的还要多，然而……
than my father could ever hope to understand, yet...
你在桌子上没有座位。
You don't get a seat at the table.
因为我“软弱”。我恋爱了。
Because I'm "weak." I fell in love.
怎么这么弱？
How is that weak?
她找错了女人。对家人不利。
She was the wrong woman. Wrong for the family.
对他来说是错误的。
Wrong for him.
那时，我非常渴望得到他的认可。
And, back then, I was so desperate for his approval.
她怎么了？
What happened to her?
可怕的事情。
Terrible things.
我让他把她吓跑了。
I let him scare her away from me.
具有讽刺意味的是，这只能证明他一开始对我的看法是正确的。
Which, ironically, only proved that he was right about me in the first place.
虚弱的。一种尴尬。
Weak. An embarrassment.
对不起，我不是故意的……
I'm sorry, I don't mean to...
为什么我觉得我可以和你说话？
Why do I feel like I can talk to you?
呃，我，嗯...
Uh, I, um...
我只是...
I just...
不好了。不，对不起，我...
Oh, no. No, I'm sorry, I...
我不能……我们不能。
I can't... we can't.
离她远点。
Get away from her.
布鲁斯！
Bruce!
等待。布鲁斯？韦恩？
Wait. Bruce? Wayne?
布鲁斯韦恩是蝙蝠侠？
Bruce Wayne is the Batman?
阿尔贝托·法尔科内 (Alberto Falcone) 是假期。
And Alberto Falcone is holiday.
处处惊喜。
Surprises all around.
我？你被灌输了一些不好的线索，布鲁斯。
Me? You've been fed some bad clues, Bruce.
但我还是解决了这个难题。
But I still solved the puzzle.
被拒绝的儿子
The rejected son,
为继承帝国而生，却被抛弃。
born to inherit an empire, but cast aside.
你错了。
You're wrong.
你知道你永远不会得到王国的钥匙，
You knew you'd never be handed the keys to the kingdom,
所以你制造了一场针对家族企业的危机。
so you manufactured a crisis that targets the family business.
什么？
What?
随着潜在的继任者像苍蝇一样下降，
With potential successors dropping like flies,
poppa只对家人收紧了圈子，
poppa tightened the circle to family only,
而且，这是第一次，你在里面。
and, for the first time, you were on the inside.
我不想控制家人！
I don't want control of the family!
我从没干过！
I never did!
十！九！八！七！六！五！
Ten! Nine! Eight! Seven! Six! Five!
四个！三！
Four! Three!
我很乐意用它换取正常的生活！
I would happily trade that for a normal life!
尽可能远离哥谭市度过我的日子。
To spend my days as far away from Gotham as possible.
二！一！新年快乐！
Two! One! Happy new year!
为了结婚生子...
To get married, and have a child with...
我的天啊！
Oh, my god!
你不可能知道。
You couldn't know.
你少了很多东西。
You're missing so many pieces.
来吧。
Come on.
吉姆，我们到底在做什么？
Jim, what the hell are we doing?
哦。
Oh.
潜水员将在阿尔贝托法尔科内的部分海域捕鱼数日。
The divers will be fishing out parts of Alberto Falcone for days.
五刃螺旋桨以最慢的速度运行。
Fivebladed prop on its slowest speed.
地狱的路要走。
Hell of a way to go.
他不是这样走的。
That isn't how he went.
他在过火之前在假期中被枪杀。
He was shot by holiday before going overboard.
不挂断。阿尔贝托不是假期吗？
Hang on. Alberto wasn't holiday?
我以为他是。
I thought he was.
这是奥卡姆剃刀，吉姆，最简单的解决方案。
It was occam's razor, Jim, the simplest solution.
但这是错误的。
But it was wrong.
我去那里是为了阿尔贝托法尔科内。
I went there for Alberto Falcone.
我以为我应该阻止他，
I thought I was supposed to stop him,
但我应该救他。
but I was supposed to save him.
他是无辜的。而现在他死了。
He was innocent. And now he's dead.
我需要变得更好。
I needed to be better.
我们都做到了。
We all did.
我们所有人。
All of us.
你必须在胭脂红法尔康上放置一个保护细节。
You have to put a protective detail on carmine Falcone.
如果他甚至会让你。
If he'll even let you.
你有没有意识到我们一开始试图摧毁罗马人，
Do you realize we started out trying to take down the Roman,
而现在，我们正试图拯救他？
and, now, we're trying to save him?
什么时候发生的？
When did that happen?
我有一个更好的问题。
I have a better question.
如果阿尔贝托法尔科内不是假期……那么谁是？
If Alberto Falcone wasn't holiday... Then who is?
下一个是谁？
And who's next?
让我们的兄弟可以睡在这里
Grant that our brother may sleep here
在平静中，直到你唤醒他的荣耀，
in peace until you awaken him to glory,
因为你就是复活和生命。
for you are the resurrection and the life.
然后他会看到你面对面
Then he will see you face to face
在你的光中会看到光
and in your light will see light
并知道神的光辉。
and know the splendor of god.
阿门。
Amen.
布鲁斯。
Bruce.
一个字。
A word.
胭脂红。如果有什么我可以做的。
Carmine. If there's anything I can do.
你知道我想让你做什么，但你一次又一次地拒绝我。
You know what I want you to do but, time and time again, you refuse me.
韦恩基金会不是暴徒的洗钱机构。
The Wayne foundation isn't a moneylaundering outfit for the mob.
它不会，只要我能控制。
And it won't be, so long as I'm in control.
当然。
Of course.
哦，我多么粗鲁。
Oh, how rude of me.
我不相信你见过我的同事。
I don't believe you've met my associate.
迷住了。
Charmed.